Emmanuel Yegon

https://github.com/emmanuel-yegon in www.linkedin.com/in/emmanuel-yegon-4b382324b

Profile

Computer scientist passionate and curious about handling of data various domains. Data scientist with experience in building data-intensive applications. Proficient in predictive modelling, data processing and data mining algorithms as well as scripting languages including python. Capable of developing and deploying machine learning models.

Draiacts

Projects	
09/2021 – 04/2022	Sentiment Analysis On Movie Reviews ☑ Created a web application system that can be able to distinguish movie reviews as either positive or negative using a convolutional neural network model. The model used was through transfer learning. It is a pretrained model developed by google
01/2021 - 02/2021	Loan ELigibility Prediction Model ☑ Created a machine learning model using python to predict if a person will default on a loan payment.
03/2021 - 03/2021	House Price Prediction Model ☑ Developed a machine learning model and deployed it using a streamlit python framework. The model can predict house prices based on certain features such as the number of bedrooms.

06/2021 - 06/2021 Data Analytics On Sales Data 🛮

Analyzed sales data using python libraries such as pandas, numpy, sklearn, and matplotlib for visualizing the data. Derived insights by identifying insights such as

- Products brought together by customers
- Products with high sales volume

Reports and Dashboards using Power BI and Tableau 🛮 01/2020 - present

- Analyzed data using Microsoft power bi by creating reports and dashboards of various datasets such as sales data of products. In these sales data, I created a sales performance dashboard.
- Through the creation of power Bi dashboards, I wrote DAX expressions to aid in the analysis of data.
- Created data models which enabled me to connect to different tables in Power Bi reports. These data models lead to the building of relationships between the data tables.
- Analyzed data using tableau by creating dashboards to show the trends of data and get insights from them.

Skills

- Data Visualization
- SQL
- React JS

- Data Cleaning
- Python
- Machine Learning
- R Language

- Data Analysis
- Pandas
- Deep Learning
- java spring boot

Microservices

• Data Science

Professional Experience

05/2022 - present

Support Engineer, Baran Telcom Networks

Currently, I'm working as a support enginner at Baran. Roles and responsibilities assigned include SDWAN and IT support roles:

Sofware defined WAN roles

- Deployement of new customers using versa director,
- Upgrading SDWAN CPEs devies remotely,
- Installation of flexVNF software in ETX-2v devices,
- Continuous active monitoring of the SDWAN gateways using moba-xterm software,
- Updated licenses running in SDWAN gateways.

IT Support Roles

- Creation of staff mail in active directory,
- · Resetting passwords for users,
- Troubleshooting printing problems such as paper jams,
- Issuing of laptops,
- Resetting of laptops and installation of new OS.

09/2021 - 11/2021

Attachee, Kenya Revenue Authority, Embu Office

I was attached at the KRA office located in Embu town. Took part in offering IT support to the staff. Some of the activities I did include:

- Troubleshooting of network issues.
- Deployment of new computers.
- Troubleshooting printing problems such as paper jams.
- Crimping of network cables.
- Connection of cisco telephones with the internet.

Education

09/2017 - 04/2022	Bachelor of Science in Applied Computer Science, Chuka University.
01/2014 - 11/2017	Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education, Kericho High School.
01/2009 - 11/2013	Kenya Certificate of Primary Education, Chepseng'eny Academy.

Certificates

•	Data Visualizations Using
	Tableau

• Data Science for Everyone

Versa SDWAN Basics

• Versa Analytics Self Paced

- Versa Essentials

Chess

FootBall

• Listening to music

Travel

Interests